珍妮
Jenny?
凯特  谢天谢地
Kate. Thank God!
凯文给你打电话了吗
Um, h-have you heard from Kevin?
没有  给你打了吗
No, I haven't. Have you?
也没有  我一直在打给他
No, I've been calling him
想测试下我们的应急机制  但他都没接
to test our system and he's not answering,
我有点担心
and I'm freaking out a little bit.
你知道他在哪吗
Um, do you have any idea where he is?
凯特  在听吗
Kate? Kate, are you there?
在  我在呢
Yeah. Yeah, I'm here.
怎么回事  凯文在哪
What's going on? Where's Kevin?
珍妮  你要冷静点  好吗
Jenny, I need you to stay calm, okay?
出事了
Something's happened.
火场里的犯罪现场  还从没遇到过呢
Crime scene at a fire? Never done one of these before.
这案子之后  你可能就不想遇到了
After this, you might not want to.
这栋楼正在修葺
Building was being rehabbed,
所以是不该有人在这里的
so the place was supposed to be empty.
看来死者并不知道啊
I guess our victim didn't get that memo.
-知道死者身份了吗  -不...
- Do we know who our victim is? - Uh, no--
天哪  是珍妮
Oh, oh, oh, oh, my God. Oh, my God. It's Jenny.
她要生了  珍妮
It's go time. Hi, Jenny.
开始宫缩了吗  有没有...
Are you having contractions? Are you--
没事  是该再检查一次
No. No, it's good to double-check
我手机好不好使  或是检查三次
if my phone's working-- or triple-check.
好了  亲爱的  回聊
Okay, all right, sweetie. Talk to you soon.
假警报
False alarm.
-她预产期过了两天了  -三天了
- What is she, uh, two days past her due date? - Three.
随时都可能生
So, it could happen at any minute.
能相信吗  我要做爸爸了
Can you believe it? Me as a dad.
莱恩  你会是个好爸爸的
No, Ryan, you're gonna be great.
取好名字了吗
You guys pick a name?
没有  我们有分歧
No, we couldn't agree on one.
看是男孩还是女孩  然后再决定
So we're waiting to see if it's a boy or a girl, and then decide.
允许我建议  科斯莫
May I suggest... "Cosmo"?
不允许
No, you may not.
给我家孩子取名
And rather than pick a name for my kid,
还不如定下大婚日子
you should pick a date for your wedding.
定下大婚日子  我准备带她私奔呢
Pick a date for my wedding? I was planning on bringing her.
是吗  什么时候  说不定我有约呢
Really? When is that? I might have plans.
我叫马克·金柏尔  建筑安全部的
I'm Mark Kimball, building and safety.
你们非要进来吗
Do you guys really need to be in here?
我们的犯罪现场在这里
It's where our crime scene is.
尽量快点  不要久留
Well, don't stay any longer than you have to.
大火烧坏了房屋结构  我得撤空整栋大楼
Fire did structural damage. I need to clear the building.
我们很快的
We should be in and out.
-好吧  -谢谢
- Okay. - Thanks.
知道死者身份了吗
So, do we know who the victim is?
不知道  他有钱包  但已经烧烂了
Nope. Dude had a wallet. It's burned to a crisp.
如果是个"他"的话  已经很难分辨了
Even if he was a dude. It's even hard to tell that.
懂你意思了
I see what you mean.
事实上  他是个男人
Actually, he is a dude,
我现在差不多只能告诉你们这些
which is about all I could tell you right now.
-这是弹孔吗  -可能是九毫米口径的
- Is that a bullet hole? - Probably a nine.
不必说  这不是自然死亡
So needless to say, this wasn't from natural causes.
火灾也是人为的
Neither was the fire.
这位是德利娅·波顿副队长
This is Lieutenant Delia Burton.
纽约消防局的火灾调查员
She's a fire investigator with F.D.N.Y.
贝克特警探  卡塞尔先生
Detective Beckett. Mr. Castle.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
这是蓄意纵火吗
So this was arson?
看样子是的
Well, it's looking that way.
我在起火点找到了少量助燃剂
I found miniscule traces of accelerant at the flashpoint.
凶手为掩盖凶杀案而放火
So the killer set the fire to cover up the murder?
但尸体上却没有助燃剂
Except there's no accelerant on the body.
而起火点在这栋楼的更里面
And the fire's flashpoint is deeper in the building.
通常要处理掉一具尸体
You know, normally, when you're disposing of a body,
都会确保尸体着了火
you're gonna make sure it burns.
也许死者抓到纵火犯在放火
So maybe our victim surprised the arsonist--
纵火犯就杀了他灭口
and the arsonist killed him, silencing him as a witness?
我看挺像
That's how it looks to me.
不过凶杀案可不是我的专长
Then again, homicide's not my specialty.
但火灾是
No, uh, but fire is.
你有发现的话
Would you mind keeping me in the loop
能通知我吗
in case you find anything else?
好
Sure.
我搞清楚怎么回事就通知你
As soon as I know what happened, so will you.
-什么情况  -这栋楼
- Oh, what was that? - The building.
你们该走了
You guys should probably go.
有道理
Sounds good.
回见
See ya.
我要嫁这号人
I'm... marrying him.
去查查这地方的业主是谁吧
Uh, why don't we just look into whoever owns this place?
看他们知不知道谁会在这里
See if they know who might've been in here.
好
Right.
我不知道他是谁
I have no idea who he is.
那栋楼在翻新  不该有人在里面的
Wasn't nobody supposed to be in there on account of the renovation.
也许那家伙是个流浪汉或蹭房的吧
Maybe the guy was a bum or a squatter or something.
但也是一条人命  真是悲剧啊
But, hey, you know. Human life, still a tragedy, right?
图里奥先生  我们来谈谈为什么那里没人吧
Mr. Turino, let's talk about why no one was there.
连个保安都没有
Not even a security guard.
你三个月前停止翻新之后
Wasn't your building basically abandoned
那栋楼不是就荒废了吗
after you stopped renovations three months ago?
因为资金短缺
Due to a cash flow problem?
再说一遍你是谁
Who are you again?
我只是不禁注意到
Just someone who couldn't help but notice
你的银行给那栋楼定了很高的保险金
your bank required high levels of insurance on that building
这是给你贷款的条件
as a condition of granting you the loan.
所以呢
So?
所以一份全额保险赔付
So a total-loss insurance claim
可以解决你所有的资金流问题
would solve all of your cash flow problems.
对  不足之处是你要因为谋杀而进监狱
Right. The downside being, you'll go to prison for murder.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
我不会烧了自己的楼
I wouldn't burn down my own building.
好吧  烧楼的肯定另有其人
Okay, somebody else must've done it.
告诉我  图里奥先生
Tell me, Mr. Turino,
你跟有组织犯罪有关系吗
Are you involved in organized crime?
这话我可不爱听
I take offense to that.
就因为我是意大利人  我就是黑帮的吗
Just because I'm Italian, I'm in the mob?
不  我觉得你是黑帮成员是因为你是
No, I think you are in the mob because you're a known member
曼奈利犯罪家族的已知成员  而且你有
of the Maneri crime family, and you also have convictions
勒索  诈骗和暴力犯罪的前科
in racketeering, fraud, assault...
好吧  可我已经改过自新了
Yeah, okay. Okay. I moved on.
我已经不过那种生活了
I'm out of the life now.
我的梦想就是修复那座大楼
It was my dream to rehab that building
然后卖掉它  去博卡过退休生活
and flip it, retire to Boca.
现在那个梦想  已经灰飞烟灭了
Now that dream? It's up in smoke.
-贝克特  -怎么了
- Yo, Beckett. - Yeah?
阿特·图里奥的不在场证明确认了
So Art Turino's alibi checks out.
他昨晚在粉红宫殿绅士俱乐部
He was at the Pink Palace Gentleman's Club last night,
晚上八点到凌晨四点一直在看脱衣舞
stuffing g-strings from 8:00 P.M. To 4:00 A.M.
对  但他不代表他是清白的
Yeah, but that doesn't mean he's in the clear.
我是说  图里奥不会自己动手的
I mean, Turino wouldn't do this himself.
好吧  我去查查跟他亲近的人里
Well, I'll see if anyone he's been hanging with
有没有人跟纵火有关
has any connection to arson.
好  我去找卡塞尔
Okay, I'll grab Castle.
我们去看看蕾妮在死者身上有没有新发现
We'll see if Lanie's got anything new on our vic.
还是身份不明  他也不在失踪人口报告里
Still no I.D., and he's not in any missing person's report.
子弹有匹配结果吗
We get a match on the bullet?
系统里没有
It's not in the system,
但死因绝对是头部中枪
but the cause of death was definitely a G.S.W. to the head.
肺部没有烟尘
No smoke in the lungs,
所以起火前他就已经死了
so he was already dead before the fire got going.
总比被活活烧死好
Whoa. Beats getting roasted alive.
我同意你的观点
I'm right there with you.
而且  他很健康  满身肌肉
Also, he was healthy, muscular.
他的牙齿很整齐  所以他可能不是流浪汉
His teeth were in good shape. So he probably wasn't homeless.
再说他的医疗状况也很好
Plus he had great medical care.
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
他有一条骨折的腿...
He had a fractured leg that was splinted...
用金属板和钢钉固定着
with metal plates and screws.
-手术质量很高  -钢板可以追查来源吗
- Quality work, too. - Can the plate be traced?
我已经在查了
I'm already on it.
是左腿吗
Was it the left leg?
股骨前区  中部往下
Anterior femur, mid-way down?
是的  你怎么知道
That's right. How did you know?
我知道他是谁
I know who he is.
他是个名叫布雷克·麦凯恩的火灾调查员
He's a fire investigator named Blake McCann.
他曾经是我的搭档
He was my partner.
好的  知道了  蕾妮
Okay. Got it, Lanie.
牙科记录确认了受害者就是布雷克·麦凯恩
So dental records confirm that our victim is Blake McCann.
我很遗憾
I'm very sorry.
他是个好人
He was a good man.
我见过的最正直的人
Most decent person I ever knew.
你知道他认识的人里
Do you know of anyone in his life
有谁想要伤害他吗
that would've wanted to hurt him?
只有留下这个的人
Just the person who left this.
我在火灾现场发现的
I found it at the fire scene.
这是什么
What is it?
这个图案是由助燃剂产生的
This pattern is made by accelerant.
根据这种图案来看  可能是过氧化苯乙酰
From the staining pattern, probably benzoyl peroxide,
从管子里挤出来的
Squeezed from a tube.
布雷克在另外十个火灾现场也发现了同样的图案
Blake found the same pattern in ten other burned buildings.
那么这是个标志
So it's a signature?
一个连环纵火犯的标志
Of a serial arsonist.
布雷克已经追踪这家伙好几年了
Blake has been hunting this guy for years.
他所有空闲时间都在干这个
It's how he spent every spare minute.
他刚刚开始利用假期来查这个案子
In fact, he had just taken some vacation days to work the case.
当我发现这个标志时  我给他打了电话
When I found the symbol, I called him.
他没有回电话  我...
He didn't call me back. I, uh...
我有一种很糟的感觉
I just had an awful feeling.
他知道纵火犯是谁吗  有嫌疑人吗
Did he know who the arsonist is? Did he have any suspects?
他从没跟我说过
Not that he ever told me.
他只是称他为"幻影"
He just called him "The phantom,"
因为他总能在人们注意不到的时候
Because he seemed to be able to slip in and out
溜进大楼又溜出来
of buildings without people ever noticing.
直到目前为止
Until now, maybe.
应该就是这样  对吧
Well, that's gotta be it, right?
布雷克去了那座大楼
I mean, Blake went in that building
因为他在追那个家伙
because he was after the guy.
就是那家伙杀了他
And that's who killed him.
现在下结论还太早  但这是个切入点
It's too soon to know, but it's a place to start.
我们需要他的那些关于纵火犯的
Now, we're gonna need copies of his case files
案件资料
linked to the arsonist.
他带了一些回家
Well, he took a bunch of them home with him.
我会让探员去拿的
I'll have detectives pick them up.
剩下的在办公室  我会给你拿来
The rest are at the office. I'll get them over to you.
很好
Great.
我跟布雷克·麦凯恩的同事和前妻聊过了
So, I talked to Blake McCann's co-workers, his ex-wife,
如果他有什么敌人  那我没找到
and if he's got any enemies, I am not finding them.
那就只剩下了"幻影"
Leaving us with the phantom.
你能别那么叫他吗
Can you please not call him that?
听起来很傻
It just--it sounds silly.
比"纵火犯"还傻  那个词里有个"犯"
Sillier than the "Arsonist"? Which starts with "Arse"?
至少"幻影"听起来有点神秘感
At least with "the phantom" he's got some mystique.
他不配有神秘感  他是个谋杀犯
He doesn't deserve mystique. He's a murderer.
但杀人不是他通常的犯罪手法
Yeah, but killing is not a part of his usual M.O.
目前为止  所有他烧掉的大楼都是空的
Until now, all the buildings he torched were empty.
好吧  那这些大楼还有什么共同点
Okay. All right, so what else do they have in common?
不太多  所有的建筑都比较破旧
Not much. All the buildings were older,
但有些是民宅  有些是办公楼
but some were residential, some were office buildings.
其中有两所在曼哈顿  剩下的在布鲁克林
There were two in Manhattan and the rest in Brooklyn
-还有皇后区  -所有的大楼都有保险吗
- and in Queens. - Were they insured?
有几栋有  但是并不是所有
A couple of them, but not all of them.
所以大概不是受雇的纵火犯
So it probably was not arson-for-hire.
也就是说他是出于一己私欲
Which means he's doing this for himself.
为了满足内心的欲望而纵火
He's burning these buildings to satisfy an inner need.
就跟连环杀手一样
And like a serial killer,
他选择这些建筑纵火是有原因的
there's a reason why he chooses the buildings he does.
肯定存在某种规律
There's a pattern or something.
-怎么啦  -三天前有条记录  麦凯恩写下了一个名字
- What? - Entry from three days ago. Mccann wrote down a name.
亚当·弗格森
Adam Ferguson.
-安全  -安全
- Clear. - Clear.
除了我们还有其他人对布雷克·麦凯恩感兴趣
I'd say someone besides us is interested in Blake McCann.
看来他死后这里被人翻了个底朝天
Yeah, looks like this place was tossed after he was killed.
你跟我想的一样吗
You thinking what I'm thinking?
纵火犯杀了他之后
That the arsonist shot him
得知麦凯恩留下了书面记录
and then got word McCann left a paper trail.
他到这来找那些能引向他的
He came here searching for any files or evidence
文件和证据
that would point to him.
或许凶手翻得这么乱是因为找不到文件
Maybe our prep tossed the place because he couldn't find them.
可麦凯恩没有理由把资料藏起来
But McCann had no reason to hide those files.
他应该会放在饭桌  办公桌或床头上
They'd be out on a table, a desk or a nightstand.
等等
Wait.
麦凯恩的车  没有停在车道上
McCann's car. It wasn't in the driveway.
也没有在车库
Or in the garage.
他可能是死之前开车去了那栋楼
He probably drove it to that building before he was killed.
车可能还在那
It could still be down there.
对  资料也可能在车上
Yeah, with those files in it.
找到了  亚当·弗格森
Here it is. Adam Ferguson.
因多次纵火入狱
And Blake McCann helped put him away
布雷克·麦凯恩指证了他
on multiple arson counts.
他五年前出狱了
He got out of prison five years ago.
这么凑巧  那也恰好就是
Which, by wild coincidence, is right about the same time
开始发生大楼纵火案的时候
those buildings started getting torched.
不仅如此  看下这个
Not only that, but check this out.
看看布雷克在被害前一天打给了谁
Look at who Blake called on his cell the day before he was killed.
没错  布雷克·麦凯恩确实给我打了电话
Yeah, Blake McCann Called me.
你们谈了些什么
To talk about what?
就是朋友之间的闲聊
Just a chat between friends.
昨晚九点到凌晨一点你在哪  弗格森先生
Where were you last night between 9 and 1 a.m., Mr. Ferguson?
怎么了
Why?
他被一个他所追踪的纵火犯杀掉了
Because he was murdered by an arsonist he was hunting.
那真是太可惜了
Well, that's a real shame.
凶手跟你一样  也是纵火犯
An arsonist not unlike yourself.
事实上  他临死之前
Matter of fact, one of his final acts
还写下了你的名字
was to write down your name.
这可不是因为我杀了他
Not because I killed him.
肯定是"幻影"干的  我不知道他的真名
It must've been the phantom. I don't know his real name.
那你怎么知道这个人
How do you know about him at all?
布雷克跟我说的
Blake told me.
他给我打了电话
He called me.
约我在格林威治一家熟食店见面
Asked me to meet him in some deli in the village.
他完全不知道该怎么抓到这个"幻影"
He was all stalled out about catching this phantom guy.
他向我寻求帮助  我答应帮他
He asked for my help, and I said I'd give it to him.
即使是他把你送进了监狱
Even though he put you in prison?
布雷克补偿了我
Blake paid me for my time.
此外
Plus, uh,
他让我欣赏了那些大火的照片
he let me see some photos of the fires.
所以说我们双方都有好处
So we both got something out of the deal.
你还跟他说了什么锦囊妙计
And what other wisdom did you offer him?
任何笨蛋都会洒点汽油  点根火柴
Any idiot can slosh gas around and light a match.
可这个人  他懂火  知道怎么让大火蔓延
But this guy? He knew fire, knew how it spread.
你知道吗  楼房就跟人一样
See, buildings are just like people.
都有一个弱点  一个容易受到攻击的部位
There's a weak spot, a soft underbelly.
他能够找到它  利用它
He would find it, use it,
几乎不用任何催化剂就可以掀起一场地狱之火
unleash an inferno with barely any accelerant.
那人
That...
简直就是一位艺术家
is an artist.
这些怎么帮到麦凯恩
So how did any of this help McCann?
我给了他一些建议
I gave him some tips.
我告诉他  他要找的这个人
I told him he was looking for someone
会非常仔细地踩点
who cases buildings carefully.
在行动之前会去查看几次大楼
Visits them a few times before he strikes.
还有呢
What else?
像"幻影"这样的艺术家  他会去欣赏他的杰作
An artist like the phantom? He wants to admire his work.
仅仅放火是不够的
It's not enough that he sets the fire.
他需要感受火焰的热度
He needs to feel the heat.
聆听火场的乐声
To listen to the music.
火焰的咆哮  房屋被击溃时的哀鸣
The roar of the flames, the moans of the buildings as they give in--
这才是他所渴求的
that's what he lives for.
所以  他每次纵火
Which is why with every fire he sets,
他都会在场观赏
he is there watching.
你们怎么看他说的这些
What do you make of his story?
他说他和麦凯恩见面的那个熟食店
The staff at the deli where he said he met with McCann
那里的店员记得他们
remembers seeing them.
但是却不知道他们俩说了些什么
There's no way to really know what they talked about.
麦凯恩可能是在说他就是"幻影"
McCann could've accused hime of being the phantom.
也许他就是
Maybe he is the phantom.
我们还没有任何证据能将他
We don't have anything that links him
和任何一场纵火案联系起来  所以
to any of the arsons yet, so...
仔细调查他不在场的证据和他的朋友
Dig into his alibi and associates.
看能否找到可靠的证据
See if you can find anything that's solid.
好的
Okay.
他说的这些当中有一点
You know, one thing about his story
听上去很真实  在人物性格上
that does ring true-- on a character level--
也就是纵火犯享受火灾的过程
is about how the arsonist watches his own fires.
警员正在排查火灾现场
Yeah, well, I've got UNIs canvassing the fire scene
并检查附近的监控录像
and checking into all the security cameras
找案发时在周围逗留的人
in the area for anyone that was hanging out.
找到麦凯恩的车了
Yo, found McCann's car.
距失火地点两条街
It was parked two blocks from the fire,
车里有东西
and there was something inside.
纵火案记录
Arson files?
不  貌似是两份他自己搜集的资料
No, looks like a couple of files that he put together himself.
其中一份记录就是他遇害的大楼
One's about the building that he was burned up in.
另一份呢
What's the other one?
拿过来
Give me that.
布鲁克林阿卡迪亚街的一个旧鞋厂
It's an old shoe factory in brooklyn on Arcadia Lane.
空了五年了
Looks like it's been empty for five years.
这些可能是麦凯恩认为
You know, maybe those files were on buildings
会是纵火目标的建筑
that McCANN thought were being targeted.
还对了一个
He was right about one of them.
埃斯波  我们认为纵火犯
Listen, espo, we believe that the arsonist
会事先对目标进行踩点
cases the buildings he burns.
去看下那个工厂  看看有没有可疑人物出入
So check that factory, and see if anyone suspicious has been seen inside.
这就去
We're on it.
真是的  瞧啊
Man, look at this place.
-失过火的都比这干净  -是啊
- Fire would be an improvement. - Yeah.
貌似很久没人出入了
Looks like no one's set foot in here in years.
好恐怖
It's pretty creepy.
相信我  兄弟  你电话开着呢
Trust me, bro, your ringer is all the way up.
就是确认一下
Just wanted to make sure.
珍妮随时都可能打来
Jenny might call me at any minute.
你盯着也没用
Pulling your phone out isn't gonna make it happen any sooner.
你得镇定
You just need to chill.
说的好听  好像你多有经验似的
And... you know this from your vast experience of having zero kids?
我知道你现在很激动
All right, you know what? You're all emotional right now.
所以我原谅你
So I'm gonna let that go. Hmm.
好了  走吧
All right. Let's get back.
这没什么了
There's nothing to see here.
等等
Oh, wait a minute.
废弃大楼里怎么会有新锁
Abandoned building with a brand-new lock?
警察  有人吗
N.Y.P.D.! Anybody here?!
-安全  -安全
- All clear. - Clear.
不是吧
What the hell?
哈维  雷管
Javi, these are blasting caps here.
还有很多助燃剂
And accelerants up the wazoo.
看
Look.
这哪是纵火目标  根本就是他的工作间
This isn't the arsonist's next target. It's his workshop.
我们触响警报了
We must've set off an alarm.
不是警报
It's not an alarm!
出去  快
Get out. Get out now!
我查了失火点附近的监控摄像头
So I checked the security cameras near the fire.
被破坏了
They were disabled.
怎么弄的
Disabled how?
有人爬上了电线杆
Someone used a can of spray paint,
用喷漆涂了镜头
mounted it on a pole, and blacked out the lenses
两处都是失火前几分钟
of both cameras just minutes before the fire.
肯定是纵火犯干的
Well, that must've been the arsonist.
可能会有目击者
Maybe somebody saw them do it.
能调查一下周围吗  当然我不行
Can we canvass the area? And by "We," I mean,
得找别人
obviously, somebody else.
你看什么呢
What are you looking for?
别告诉我
And don't tell me.
是在工作场所不该看的吧
It's something completely inappropriate for the workplace.
这次不是  因为现在
No, not this time. Uh, given that everyone
大家什么东西都上传
uploads everything to the internet nowadays,
我想或许有人
I thought I might see
拍了火灾现场的视频  瞧啊
if anyone else out there took a video of that fire, and look.
如果纵火犯真在现场
If the arsonist was watching that fire,
说不定会拍到他
He might be in this video.
-声音开大点  -好
- Can you turn up the sound? - Yeah.
不对劲
That doesn't look right.
怎么了
Seriously?
这可比监控录像清晰多了啊
A lot better quality than a security camera.
是大楼不对劲
No, babe, I'm talking about the building.
刚起火
That fire just started.
想到什么了
"Huh," What?
没有消防队
Fire department's not even there.
甚至都没网那赶呢
I mean, they're not on their way.
听不到消防车鸣笛
You can't hear the sirens.
没人知道着火了  录像者是怎么知道的
So how did the cameraman know there was a fire when nobody else did?
你听
And listen to that.
他没有在喊人报警
He's not yelling for anyone to call 9-1-1.
他很沉默
He's not saying anything.
拍摄平稳流畅
Look at the camera work-- very smooth, steady.
-你不会认为  -没错
- You--you don't think-- - Yeah. I do.
这不仅仅是火灾视频
This isn't just footage of the fire.
这就是纵火犯拍的
It was shot by the arsonist.
发布视频的人就是纵火犯
We have to track down whoever posted that video.
抓到你了
Got you.
很麻烦
That won't be so easy.
一般视频里都嵌有相机数据
Usually there's a file embedded in the video with data on the camera,
但是这里的被删除了
but it's been stripped out.
能查到是在哪上传的吗
Can you tell where it was first uploaded?
稍等
Let me see.
看来这个视频在网上流传很广
Looks like the video got bounced around the net from site to site,
这是首发
But this is where it started.
炙爱网站  开玩笑吧
Pyrolicious.com. Really?
哇  好吧
Wow. Okay.
一个专门满足恋火癖的网站
A site that caters to fire fetishists.
我都不知道还有恋火癖这么个东西
I didn't even know there was a fire fetish.
准确的说法是"火焰嗜好"
The actual term is "Pyrophilia."
更加有力地证明只要你想得到  在网上就找得到
Further proof that the Internet has something for everyone.
我就不深究你是怎么知道这种事的了
I'm not gonna ask how you knew that.
那么这段视频是什么时候发布的
So when did this video show up there?
大约在大火被扑灭后一个小时
About an hour after the fire was put out.
谁在经营这网站
And who runs this site?
这网站注册在麦罗·帕弗里克名下
It's registered to a Milo Pavlik.
他有犯罪记录吗
Does he have a record?
还真有  他19岁时把自己家烧了
Oh, yeah. He burnt down his family house when he was 19.
我们该上哪找这个麦罗·帕弗里克
Where do we find this Milo Pavlik?
麦罗·帕弗里克  纽约警察  快开门
Milo Pavlik! N.Y.P.D., open up!
干啥  喂  你这是要干什么
What? Hi, hey. What are you doing?
这段视频哪来的
Where did this video come from?
你等下  我什么非法的事都没做
Listen, nothing I do here is illegal.
我只不过在为各国火焰爱好者提供...
I-I simply provide fire enthusiasts around the globe--
这场大火是一个纵火犯引起的
This fire was set by an arsonist.
而且还害死了人
Not to mention a murderer.
那这视频是谁拍的  你吗
So who shot this video? Was it you?
不是  说啥  当然不是我
No. What? It w--it wasn't me.
那怎么挂到你的网站上去了
Then how'd it get up on your site?
稍等  有短信
Sorry, it's a text.
管你有啥  到底是怎么发到你的网站上的
I don't care. How did it get up on your site?
我在外面有个投物箱  有人往里放东西
I have a drop-box outside. People leave stuff.
这视频存在一个闪存盘上
It was on a U.S.B. drive.
这是优质素材  所以我就上传了
It was quality material, so I uploaded it.
谁给你的闪存盘
Who dropped it off?
不知道  我完全不知道
I don't know. I have no idea.
你推得倒轻巧  那这个人还有没有
That's very convenient. Now, did this person
提供什么别的"素材"
ever provide any other material?
当然有  这人绝对有眼光
Oh, yeah. H-he has a real eye, this one.
送给我不少干货
Sent me a few choice items.
如果上传这些视频的真的另有其人
If it really was someone else and they're submitting videos,
那此人一定时常光顾这网站
then he visits the site.
我需要你的网站过去五年
I'm gonna need the names of all of your members
所有的注册用户信息和网站流量记录
along with records of site traffic over the past five years.
那你就得出示搜查令了
Pretty sure you need a warrant for that.
除非你自愿提供给我
Not if you agree to cooperate...
我强烈推荐你这么做
which I highly encourage you to do.
谁一个劲地给你发短信
Hey, who the hell keeps texting you?
这是即时新闻提醒
It's a news alert.
布鲁克林区现在有一场三级火警
There's a 3-alarm fire going in Brooklyn.
布鲁克林的什么地方
Where in Brooklyn?
阿卡迪亚巷的某间工厂
Uh, some factory on Arcadia Lane.
糟了
Oh, no.
没人接  莱恩和埃斯波西托都打不通
Still no answer. Not from Ryan or Esposito.
探长  你确定他们困在里面了吗
Detective. Are you sure they're inside?
是的  他们去查探一栋
Yeah, they were checking the building
与一起纵火谋杀案有关的建筑
in connection with an arson homicide,
而到现在都没回话
and they haven't called in yet.
你得提醒一下搜救队
You need to alert your rescue teams.
探长  整座建筑都烧起来了
Detective, the building's fully involved.
我不得不命令所有突进组队员撤出来
I just had to pull out the interior attack teams.
等火势稍被控制之后我才能派搜救队进去
I can't send in a rescue company until it's more contained.
什么  还要控制
Wait, more contained?
如果我的人在里面  你就得把他们救出来
If my guys are in there, I need you to bring them out.
我们要是能突进去  肯定早就进去了
If we could get in there, I would.
但建筑物内部已经开始坍塌了
But there's been a partial collapse inside.
我差点赔了六个弟兄在里面
I almost lost six of my guys.
我们会拼尽全力  探长
We'll do everything we can, Detective,
但这建筑火势太猛  每一层都是
but this building's a firestorm. Every floor.
要是你同事真的在里面  那我很遗憾
If your guys are in there, I'm sorry.
他们可能已经殉职了
They're probably already gone.
队长
Chief?
这场火灾
Fire.
怎么烧起来的
What started it?
破损的窗户和建筑结构损毁
Shattered windows and structural damage
表明是由爆炸引发的
indicate some kind of explosion.
也许
Maybe, um...
也许他们本来就不在里面
Maybe they weren't inside.
他俩的车在这  又没回话  他们就在里面
Their car's here and they haven't called. They're inside.
我当初就不该派他们进去
I shouldn't have let them go in.
不该让他们单枪匹马去  我应该...
Not alone. I should've--
这种事你怎么预料得到
There's no way you could've known that.
这不怪你
This isn't you.
怪那纵火犯
It's the arsonist.
是珍妮
It's Jenny.
她为什么打给你
Why would she be calling you?
也许她那里有他们的消息
Maybe she's heard from them.
也许她已经知道他们平安了
Maybe she knows that they're safe.
珍妮
Jenny?
凯特  谢天谢地
Kate. Oh, thank God.
凯文给你打电话了吗
Um, h-have you heard from Kevin?
没有  给你打了吗
No, I haven't. Have you?
也没有  我一直在打给他  想测试下我们的应急机制
No. I've been calling him to test our system,
但他都没接
And he's not answering.
我有点担心
And I'm--I'm freaking out a little bit. Um...
你知道他在哪吗
Do you have any idea where he is?
凯特  你还在听吗
Kate? Kate, are you there?
在  我在呢
Yeah. Yeah, I'm here.
怎么回事  凯文在哪
What's going on? Where's Kevin?
珍妮  你要冷静点  好吗
Jenny, I need you to stay calm, okay?
出事了
Something's happened.
在消防员奋力将火势控制住之后
And as firefighters struggle to bring the blaze under control,
我们得以确认有两名纽约警局的警探
we now have unconfirmed reports that two N.Y.P.D. detectives
因这场爆炸被困在建筑内
were inside the building at the time of the explosion.
我们将为您实时追踪最新消息
We'll be bringing you live updates as the news comes in.
长官  这是真的吗
Sir, is it true?
我们还不知道
We don't know.
目前所掌握的情况是
What we do know is that
莱恩警探和埃斯波西托警探去调查
Detectives Ryan and Esposito were investigating
那栋建筑和系列纵火案的联系
that building for ties to a serial arsonist.
那栋建筑发生的爆炸
And it's possible that the explosion in that building
很有可能是同一个纵火犯故意为之
was deliberately set by that same arsonist--
怀疑他与其他十起火灾有关
A man suspected in ten other fires,
而且涉嫌谋杀了一名
as well as the murder of a member
纽约消防局的成员
of the New York Fire Department.
如果情况属实
And if it is true,
那么这个变态挨千刀的混蛋
then this sick son of a bitch
往他的罪恶清单里加了我们两位同事
has just added two of our own to his list.
在你们桌子上  会找到关于
On your desk, you will find copies of all the files
每起纵火案的资料
we have on each one of these arsons.
在里面  会发现蛛丝马迹
Somewhere in there, there is a trail.
在里面  线索会帮我们查清他的身份
Somewhere in there, there is a clue as to who he is.
我们要把他绳之以法
And he needs to be brought to account.
莱恩
Ryan!
凯文  凯文  是你吗
Kevin! Kevin, is that you?
你还好吗
You all right?
我还好
Yeah, yeah.
我动不了
Aah, I can't move.
腿被压着了
My legs are stuck.
太重了
It's too heavy! Oh...
这里像个火炉  你应该逃出去  兄弟
It's an oven in here. You should get out, man.
要走一起走  搭档
Not without you, partner.
我记得最后一件事是地板塌陷了
Last thing I remember is the floor giving way.
你觉得我们下坠了几层
How far do you think we fell?
至少有两层
At least two floors.
他肯定非法改造过这地方
Ah, must've rigged this place...
以防被发现  用来销毁一切证据
Probably to destroy any evidence in case it was found.
是啊  也包括我们
Yeah, including us.
不会让他得逞的
Not if I can help it.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- You ready? - Yeah.
好的  我开始搬了
All right, here we go.
他们很机敏  会没事的
They're smart. They're survivors.
如果房子里面有安全的地方
If there's a safe place inside that building,
他们会找到的  他们可能还活着
they may have found it. They may still be alive.
是啊  但能撑多久呢
Yeah, but for how long?
麦凯恩车里的那两个文件夹
The two folders in McCann's car--
他知道这栋建筑是下一个目标  怎么知道的
he knew that this building was next. How?
不知为何  他摸清了了纵火者的套路
Somehow, he must've figured out the arsonist's pattern.
也就是说是有套路可寻的
Which means there is a pattern.
如果他能摸清套路  那我们也能
And if he figured it out, so can we.
往后退
Move back!
所有人都后退
Everybody back!
往后退
Move back!
怎么回事
What's going on?
这栋楼全烧了
This building's gone.
我们得把工作重心转移到安全防范
We have to move to a defensive attack.
其他的建筑物面临危险
The other structures are in danger.
你们就这么放弃了吗
You're just giving up?
不  我们只是去排查其他的建筑
No, our teams just went through
它们同样可能发生火灾
the other buildings. They're tinderboxes.
如果继续这样下去  有可能烧毁整个街区
If we don't hold the line, we could lose the whole block.
凯特
Kate.
天花板随时可能塌陷
That ceiling's gonna give way at any minute.
你得赶快离开这
You need to get out of here, okay?
闭嘴
Shut up.
我正救你的命呢
I'm trying to save your life.
好的
Here we go.
就这
There.
稳住
Hold on.
好的
Yeah.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
快点  快 快 快
Aah! Go, go, go, go, go, go!
我没事  我没事
I'm okay! I'm okay!
-走得动吗  -不知道  拉我一把  我可以的
- Can you walk? -I don't know. Give me a hand. I'm okay.
站着
Come on.
感觉如何
How's it feel?
能站起来
I can stand.
我们在哪呢
Where are we?
看起来像是下层地下室
Looks like some kind of sub-basement.
没看见有门
I don't see any doors.
你看
Look.
看来我们要从那出去
Looks like that was our way out.
上面烧着呢  还是算了
Yeah, I don't think we wanted to go up anyway.
没有救援我们出不去
We're not gonna get out without help.
我的手机掉下来的时候坏掉了
My phone's busted from the fall.
你的呢
How about you?
收不到信号
Uh... yeah, I got nothing.
这么严重的火灾
All right, well, as big as this thing is,
消防部门一定在外面
fire department's gotta be out there.
他们一定在火灾现场
They gotta be on scene.
我们应该让他们知道我们在这下面
Yeah. We should let them know that we're down here.
是啊
Yeah.
有人听到吗  我们在下面
Anybody hear us?! Down here!
有人在上面吗
Anybody up there?!
我们在下面
We're down here!
嘿  在下面
Hey! Down here!
火烧得太旺  他们听不到
Fire's too loud. They can't hear us.
我有个主意
I got an idea.
也许敲击声会传上去
Maybe the sound will carry up.
-让他们知道我们在下面  -好主意
- Let 'em know we're down here. - Yeah.
嘿  下面
Down here! Hey!
有人吗  我们在下面
Hey! Down here, anybody!
有人吗
Come on! Hey!
我们在下面
Hey! Down here! Hey!
快点
Hey!
行了
Stop!
什么
What?
他们听不到的
They can't hear us.
那也不能放弃啊
We can't just quit, man.
要保存体力
Gotta save our strength.
然后干什么
For what?
没人知道我们在下面
Nobody knows we're down here.
这里残存的氧气
It's only a matter of time before the fire
迟早会被这场火烧光
sucks all the oxygen out of the room.
应该有办法  离开这里的
Gotta be some way... outta here,
还有其他办法让他们知道  我们在这里
some other way of letting them know that we're down here.
是吗  比如呢
Yeah? Like what?
我不知道  总有办法
I don't know. Somethin'.
好吧
Yeah.
除非你有一个氧气罐
Well, unless you have... an oxygen tank,
一对翅膀  以及一套防火服
a pair of wings, and a nomex suit...
我们会被煮熟的
We're gonna cook.
嗯
Yeah.
也许不会
Maybe not.
他们要撤退了是什么意思
What do you mean they're pulling back?
现场勘察队反映  这个建筑构造很脆弱
According to the I.C., the building is structurally
不适合派队员进去
compromised and they can't get their men in.
他们改变了策略
At this point, they don't feel
不再进行搜救活动
that it's a rescue operation anymore.
而是努力防止火势扩散
It's a recovery.
好吧  探长
Okay, Detective.
再有什么情况请随时通知我
Let me know if you hear anything more.
好的长官
Yes, sir.
有情况吗
Anything?
没  麦凯恩的文件显示  该建筑已经被查封
No, according to McCann's file, the building was condemned,
但这里没有任何迹象显示它是下一个目标
but there's nothing here to indicate why it was the next target.
贝克特
Beckett!
她被挡在警察设置的路障外
She was at the police barricades.
珍妮  你不该来这里的
Jenny, you shouldn't be here.
我怎么不该来  我丈夫在里面
The hell I shouldn't. My husband's in there.
怎么了
What's--what's going on?
她的子宫开始收缩了
She's having contractions.
你已经临产了吗
You're in labor?
间隔多久
How far apart?
大概五分钟吧
Five minutes, maybe.
这可不行  得送你去医院
Whoa, no. She can't-- we gotta get you to a hospital.
医护人员  这个女人要分娩了
Medic, over here. This woman's in labor.
我不会离开的  没有凯文我不会走的
No. I'm not--I'm not leaving. Not without Kevin.
珍妮  你在这里也帮不上忙
Jenny, there's nothing you can do here.
他在里面  凯特
He's inside, Kate.
万一他出不来  万一...
And if he doesn't make it out, if this is it...
我必须待在这里
I need to be here.
最起码先进救护车里等  好吗
Let me at least get you inside of an ambulance.
你得躺下  我们才能察看你的情况
You need to lie down so we can make sure that everything is okay.
好吧  可是等不到他我是不会走的
Okay, but I'm not leaving without him.
好
Okay.
我无法相信这一切
I can't believe this is happening.
简直像梦一样
This is like some kind of a dream.
我只希望快点醒来
I just keep waiting to wake up,
可我似乎无能为力
but it's like I can't do anything.
我们都无能为力
It's like there's nothing we can do.
我们只能待在这里等待
All we can do is be here for them.
有人吗
Hello?
贝克特
Beckett?
贝克特  贝克特  听得到吗
Beckett? Beckett, can you hear me?
贝克特
Beckett?
贝克特  你听得到吗
Beckett? Can you hear me, Beckett?
莱恩  莱恩  是你吗
Ryan? Ryan, is that you?
是啊  是我  贝克特  听我说
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's me, Beckett! Listen, uh...
我们进入的  那栋建筑
That building that--that we went into--
不只是纵火犯的下一个目标
uh, it wasn't just the next arson target.
是他的藏身之处
It--it was his lair.
他设置了炸弹  而我们被困在了这里
He rigged it to blow, and now we're trapped inside.
整个大楼都着火了
The whole place is in flames.
我知道  莱恩  我们就在外面
Yes, I know, Ryan. We're right outside.
整个消防队的人都在这里
We've got the whole fire department here.
我们还以为  你们死了
We thought... you guys were dead.
再没人来救我们  估计也不远了
Well, we will be soon if we don't get some help.
你们具体在大楼哪里
Exactly where in the building are you?
主地板下六米左右的地方
Some kind of sub-basement mechanical room
一个下层地下室
about 20 feet down from the main floor.
没有窗户  没有门
There's no windows, no doors.
-说不通啊  -怎么
- Well, this doesn't make any sense. - Why?
根据这些建筑图纸
Well, according to these plans,
这栋大楼的地板是浇筑的
This building has a slab foundation.
根本没有地下室
There is no basement area.
我不知道该怎么说
Well, I don't know what to tell you, pal.
这里就是个地下室
We're in some kinda basement.
所以那什么破规划肯定有问题
So there's something wrong with your freakin' plans.
他们还活着吗
They're alive?
是的  但他们被困在了一个未知区域
Yeah, but they're in an unmapped portion
一个下层地下室
of the building, a sub-basement.
消防队员无法进行搜救
The--The fire crews can't get to them.
我们得想办法
We need to find them
让他们离开那里
another way out of that room.
你觉得有其他办法吗
What makes you think there's another way out?
纵火犯安置了炸弹
The arsonist set the explosives
以防被别人发现
to go off to eradicate
好销毁一切证据
all evidence if he was ever found.
可是如果被发现时
But what if someone discovered him
他还在楼里没出来呢
while he was still in the building?
他会需要一个逃生通道
He'd need a way out.
那可能就是下层地下室
That could be the reason that sub-basement
没有在蓝图上的原因
isn't on the building plans.
我认为纵火犯篡改了蓝图
I think the arsonist doctored those plans.
为什么这么认为
What makes you think that?
莱恩说  在他的工作间里
Ryan said when they found the workspace,
他发现了一个通风井
it was right next to an open air shaft.
那个通风井直通下层地下室
That air shaft ran all the way down to the sub-basement.
你认为那是逃生通道吗
You think it's an escape route?
如果警察突袭这地方
If the cops were to raid this place,
他们把前后出口都堵死
and they're covering the front and the back
纵火犯还能往哪儿跑
of the building, where's he gonna go?
只能去蓝图上找不到的房间
To the one room that isn't on their plans.
然后把整栋楼炸掉
Then he blows the place,
里面的人全部被灭口
and everyone thinks he's been killed.
还有比在烈火中消失更好的
What better way to cover his tracks
隐匿踪迹的办法吗
than disappear in a fire.
这办法只有在那间屋子还有其他出口的情况下才能成功
But it only works if there's another way out of that room.
而知道出口在哪的人
And the only one to know that
-只有纵火犯  -我们得找到他
- would be our arsonist. - We need to find him.
长官
Sir?
我有新发现
I've got something.
我重新检查了一遍"炙爱"网站
I went back through the pyrolicious web site.
上面有六段视频是
Six of their videos are of fires
我们要找的纵火犯干的  每段视频的
attributed to our arsonist. Each was uploaded
上传时间都是在这些建筑被烧毁不久之后
to the site shortly after the buildings burned.
但有意思的是
But here's the interesting part.
有一个会员  在这些视频
One web site member logged in and viewed
刚刚被上传几分钟后
each of these videos
登陆并观看了它们
just minutes after they were posted.
而且只看了这几个
But only these videos.
就是他
That's him.
他在欣赏他的作品
He's checking out his work.
这个会员叫什么
What's this member's name?
我没有他的真实姓名  只有一个用户名
I don't have his real name. Just a user name--
放火者447
Firebug447.
-他是谁  -我不知道
- Who is he? - I don't know.
这个人在你的网站有账户
The man has an account on your web site.
你的用户都是付费的  你怎么可能不知道
You charge your users. How can you not know?
他付的是现金支票
He paid with a cashier's check
在终身会员制还开放的时候
back when I was offering a lifetime membership.
他把支票寄来的
He mailed it in.
-你在撒谎  -我发誓
- You're lying. - I swear!
我只知道他的用户名  放火者447
I only know his user name-- Firebug447.
你给我听好
You listen to me.
我们有两位警官就快被烧死了
I've got two officers about to burn.
如果你掌握关于这个人的任何信息
Now, if you know anything about this man,
要么你马上告诉我  要么我会让
you are gonna tell me, or I will bury you
背上谋杀从犯的罪名
as an accessory to murder.
有时我们会通过即时通讯软件聊天
We chat sometimes over IM.
他跟你聊什么
What would he say?
聊关于火的事  建筑物是怎么被烧毁的
We talk about fire, how buildings burn.
他有透露任何有助于我们
Did he say anything that could help us
找到他的信息吗
identify who he is?
没有  有时我会问
No. I'd sometimes ask.
但他十分小心
But he was careful.
有一次  他的确说了他纵火的原因
He did once say why he did it.
他说... 他无法忍受眼睁睁看着它们受折磨
He said he couldn't... deal with the suffering,
有时  那些病入膏肓的建筑物们
that sometimes sick and dying buildings
需要燃烧  并从痛苦中解脱
need to burn to be put out of their misery.
你确定你们没发现任何其它出口
And you're sure you don't see another way out?
如果有  也被废墟掩埋了
If there is, it's covered by debris.
有没有明确点的指示
Any idea where that way out might be?
卡塞尔正在跟建筑部门联系
Castle's on the phone with the Building Department.
看看能不能拿到原始蓝图
He's trying to get ahold of the original blueprints.
另一个出口的理论完全是我们的推测
We're assuming there even is a way out.
我们也许太高估这纵火犯了
We're giving this guy more credit than he deserves.
我俩都开始犯困了
We're both getting sleepy.
一氧化碳越来越浓
Carbon monoxide's building up.
莱恩  你听我说  你得撑住  知道吗
Ryan, you listen to me. You need to hang on, okay?
救援队马上就来了
They're coming for you.
感谢你的一番打气  但我们都知道
I appreciate the pep talk, but we both know
火烧得太厉害了  他们也不知道往哪里搜救
the fire's too hot. They don't know where to look.
不
No.
莱恩
Ryan...
电话线路估计也撑不了多久了
We're gonna lose the phone soon, Beckett, so...
有些事  需要你帮我
There's something I need you to do.
珍妮
Jenny.
什么  是谁
What? What is it?
是他
It's him.
是凯文吗
It's Kevin?
是你吗
Is it you?
真的是你吗
It's really you?
是的  是的  是我  美人儿
Yeah. Yeah, it's me, beautiful.
感谢上帝  你在哪
Oh, thank god. Where are you?
我就要生了
The baby's coming.
我在里面
I'm inside.
里面...
Inside...
很抱歉  我知道我保证过  但是...
I'm sorry. I know I promised, but...
我去不了了
I'm not gonna be there.
别那么说
Don't say that.
求求你  别那么说
Please, don't say that.
抱歉
Sorry.
我爱你胜过一切
I love you more than anything.
你记住
Remember that.
永远要记住
Always remember that.
凯文  求求你  别离开我
Kevin, please. No, don't leave me.
我也不想
I don't wanna.
我们得想个名字  给孩子
We need a name. For the baby.
我们得一起想
We need to do that together.
如果是个男孩
If it's a boy...
哈维尔
Javier.
如果是个女孩呢
And if it's a girl?
萨拉·格蕾丝  用你祖母的名字
Sarah Grace, after your grandmother.
我很爱你  凯文
I love you so much, Kevin.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too--
凯文
Kevin?
哈维尔
"Javier"?
你要给个爱尔兰裔白人孩子起名叫哈维尔
You're gonna name a white irish kid "Javier"?
不是吧  你现在要取笑我多愁善感
What? You're gonna bust on me now for being sentimental?
我觉得这是我最后的机会了
I figure it's my last chance.
不
No.
才不是
No, no.
我们会逃出这里的  一定有出去的方法
We're getting out of here. There's a way out,
我们会找到的
And we're gonna find it.
我不会离开珍妮的
I'm not leaving Jenny.
我不会让我的孩子没有爸爸的
I'm not leaving my baby without a dad.
好吗
All right?
醒醒  哈维
Hey, hey! Javi...
不不不  哈维
No, no, no, Javi.
不不不  你要是敢睡过去
No, no, no! Don't you dare fall asleep on me!
你敢试试  哈维  哈维
Don't you dare, Javi! Javi?!
我不想生  蕾妮
I don't wanna do this, Lanie.
我想让他陪我
Not without him.
我知道  亲爱的
I know, baby.
我知道  我在这儿  我陪你
I know, I'm here. I'm here. Mm.
宫缩到间隔两分钟了
Contractions are two minutes apart.
快生了
It's coming.
我们就在这儿生  我陪你  好吗
And we'll do it here. Together. Okay?
探长
Detective.
我们有发现了
We may have caught a break.
根据麦罗·帕弗里克所说  纵火犯挑选目标
According to Milo Pavlik, our arsonist picked his targets
是因为这些建筑"病入膏肓"
because the buildings were "sick and dying,"
而且"需要从痛苦中解脱"
and "needed to be put out of their misery."
所以我又检查了所有文件
So, I went back through the files,
所有的建筑检查报告
all of the building inspector reports,
发现他是对的
and he was right.
每一个目标建筑都有问题
Each of the targeted buildings had issues--
结构缺陷  线路问题  腐烂
structural defects, wiring problems, rot.
但纵火犯是怎么知道的
Okay, but how did our guy know that?
他不仅检查了这些建筑
He didn't just case the buildings.
还在里面待过
He spent time inside.
我想这就是布雷克的发现
I think that's what Blake discovered,
这是他找到这里的原因
how he got on to this place.
你们有莱恩和埃斯波西托发现的文件吗
Do you have those files that Ryan and Esposito found?
有  在这里
Yeah, right here.
建筑检查报告  谁署名的
The building inspection reports--who signed them?
马克·金柏尔
Uh, "Mark Kimball."
所有的这些文件  每一个
All of these files, each one,
他们都有一个共同点
they have one thing in common--
建筑检查员都是马克·金柏尔
The building inspector was Mark Kimball.
所以他才能进到里面
That's how he got inside the buildings,
还不被发现  那是他的工作
operated without being seen. It was his job.
这就说明他能进到建筑里
Which means he had access to the building department.
他通过这种方式修改建筑设计
That's how he was able to change building plans
还不被人发现
Without anyone knowing.
如果他就纵火犯  我们必须找到他
If he's the arsonist, we have to find him.
天呐  他就在现场
Oh, god. He's here.
金柏尔  不许动
Kimball! Don't move.
地下室  有没有出来的方法
The basement! Is there a way out?
有没有
Is there?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
去他的不知道
The hell you don't!
有没有出来的方法
Is there a way out?
在里面的人  是我的朋友
Those guys in there-- they are my friends.
如果他们死了  你跟着陪葬
If they die, you die.
是生是死
What's it gonna be?
你自己看着办
It's your choice.
看看另一个
Check the other one.
第七营救组  汇报情况
Rescue Seven, status?
第七营救组  找到他们了吗
Rescue Seven, do you have them?
第七营救组  他们还活着吗
Rescue Seven, are they alive?
那里
There.
埃斯波  埃斯波
Espo. Espo.
你们吓死我们了  伙计  吓死我们了
You scared us, buddy. You scared us.
莱恩
Ryan, hey!
你闻起来不错
You smell great.
珍妮在哪
Where's jenny?
凯文  你还活着
Kevin! You're alive.
哈维
Javi!
谢天谢地
Thank god.
你们俩都美极了
You're both beautiful.
凯文
Kevin...
我想让你见见萨拉·格蕾丝
I'd like you to meet Sarah Grace.